1).What is node.js?What was need of node.js?
Ans).......

2).What is asynchronus programming and why is it in important in javascript?
Ans).Synchronous programming means that, barring conditionals and function calls,
code is executed sequentially from top-to-bottom, blocking on long-running tasks such as network requests and disk I/O.
Asynchronous programming means that the engine runs in an event loop. When a blocking operation is needed, the request is started, 
and the code keeps running without blocking for the result. 
When the response is ready, an interrupt is fired, which causes an event handler to be run, where the control flow continues. 
In this way, a single program thread can handle many concurrent operations.

3).Code to demonstrate diffrence between synchronus and asynchronus programming?
Ans).Do coding.

4).What is callback?
Ans).Callback is an asynchronous equivalent for a function. 
A callback function is called at the completion of a given task. Node makes heavy use of callbacks.
All the APIs of Node are written in such a way that they support callbacks.
For example, a function to read a file may start reading file and return the control to the execution environment immediately so that the next instruction can be executed.
Once file I/O is complete, it will call the callback function while passing the callback function, the content of the file as a parameter. 
So there is no blocking or wait for File I/O. This makes Node.js highly scalable, 
as it can process a high number of requests without waiting for any function to return results.

5).What is event loop?
Ans).Node.js is a single-threaded application, but it can support concurrency via the concept of event and callbacks. 
Every API of Node.js is asynchronous and being single-threaded, they use async function calls to maintain concurrency.
Node uses observer pattern. Node thread keeps an event loop and whenever a task gets completed, 
it fires the corresponding event which signals the event-listener function to execute.

6).What is NPM?
Ans).Node Package Manager (NPM) provides two main functionalities −
Online repositories for node.js packages/modules which are searchable on search.nodejs.org
Command line utility to install Node.js packages, do version management and dependency management of Node.js packages.

commands:
npm --version(To check node version)
npm install express -g(Install module on your local computer)
npm install express --save(Install module on your local directory)

7).Create http server using node.js
8).What is nodemon.?
9).How to create server?
10).What are streams?
Streams are objects that let you read data from a source
or write data to a destination in continuous fashion.

11).What is Node.js Cluster module?
ANs).A cluster is a pool of similar workers running under a parent Node process. 
Workers are spawned using the fork() method of the child_processes module. 
This means workers can share server handles and use IPC (Inter-process communication) to 
communicate with the parent Node process.
11).Excetions in node.js??
Ans).coding

12).What is Forever and PM2?
Ans).Forever:
A simple CLI tool for ensuring that a given node 
script runs continuously (i.e. forever)

Nodemon:Simple monitor script for use during development of a node.js app.

PM2:Production process manager for Node.JS applications with a built-in load balancer.

13).Hosting a node in node.js?
Ans).1).Create your app.
2).Push the app to your github directory.
3).Login where you want to host.
4).Install node.js 
5).Do git clone of your code.
6).Start the code from forever and PM2.


14).How to run Node.js as a window service?
Ans).Use PM2 or Forever or use node-windows.

15).What is IIS?
Ans).IIS stands for internet information service.

16).How to host node application on IIS?
Ans).Step 1)

Install IISNode Module on IIS Server,
 you can download this module from https://github.com/tjanczuk/iisnode
When you open above link, you will see x86 or x64 binaries,
 click to download you binary.
Once you done, step ahead.


Step 2

Setup an IIS Website and create a server.js file on the application root
 and try to access http://localhost:port/server.js file.
 Once you see output like below, means Node.js application is up and running 
on IIS Server.

17).How to debug in node.js?
Ans).a)Instead of consol.log write debugger.
b).start node.js application using node debug <file name>
c).write cont
d).hit the browser .
e).repl
f).req.<tab>(In repl terminal only)
g)watch('req')
h).watchers
i).unwatch('req')
j)watchers
k).watch('req.url')
l).watchers

18).Map reduce in node.js
>db.posts.mapReduce( 
   function() { emit(this.user_id,1); }, 
	
   function(key, values) {return Array.sum(values)}, {  
      query:{status:"active"},  
      out:"post_total" 
   }
)

19).general format of map reduce
>db.collection.mapReduce(
   function() {emit(key,value);},  //map function
   function(key,values) {return reduceFunction}, {   //reduce function
      out: collection,
      query: document,
      sort: document,
      limit: number
   }
)

20).description of params in map reduce
map is a javascript function that maps a value with a key and emits a key-value pair

reduce is a javascript function that reduces or groups all the documents having the same key

out specifies the location of the map-reduce query result

query specifies the optional selection criteria for selecting documents

sort specifies the optional sort criteria

limit specifies the optional maximum number of documents to be returned


